ALEXANDER GRABOWSKI

CONTACT

□ xander@xangrab.com

- https://xangrab.com/
- Ohttps://github.com/XanGrab/
- m https://github.com/XanGrab/

PROFILE

I have been professionally developing games for the last two years, and recreationally my entire life. I am proficient in a diverse range of full-stack toolchains targeting game and web development. I can frequently be found in international fan games, hackathons, and game jams, expressing my passion for applied learning games and FOSS. I developed my leadership skills early, achieving the rank of Eagle Scout, and continued developing my leadership skills guiding competitive e-sports teams to compete at the national level and igniting passion in STEM teaching kids ages K-12. I am a lifelong, self-driven learner and problem solver.

SKILLS

- Unity, Godot, Phaser, Three.js
- Pixi.js, HLSL (Unity), GLSL (Three.js)
- C, C++, C#, TypeScript
- Node.js, NPM, Vite, Webpack
- · Github Actions, Docker
- Firebase BaaS, Real-time Database, Analytics API
- Digital Illustration, Figma, Illustator, Photoshop
- Linux Enviornments

EXPERIENCE

Gameplay Programmer at *Field Day Learning Games* **2022.01–2023.05** https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/

 Developer and junior designer on multiple projects including Wake: Tales from the Aqualab, client-side API for Open Game Data, and samller browserbased HTML5 games

Head Programming Instructor at Code Ninjas

2020.10-2022.12

https://codeninjas.com/

♦ Developed programming curriculum for kids of various backgrounds in the K-12 age range spanning JavaScript, MakeCode Arcade, Roblox Studio, and the Unity game engine

Youth Esports Coach at XP League

2020.10-2022.12

https://www.xpleague.com/

Certified youth eSports coach through the Positive Coaching Alliance. Led the Sun Prairie league's Fortnite team to compete at the North American Finals 2022

PROJECTS

WAKE: TALES FROM THE AQUALAB. Field Day Learning Games.

2022-2023

https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/play/wake/

An oceanography game targeting Chromebooks in middle school classrooms helping students learn scientific experimentation, modeling, and argumentation.

- ♦ Designed pivotal story and level layout elements of the introductory sequence for the game
- ♦ Brought gameplay systems to life in Unity, implementing user interfaces for the game's Shop, Observation Tanks, and Modeling
- \diamond Used in-house scripting tools to implement over seventy-five percent of the quests in the game

UNANNOUNCED HTML5 BROWSER GAMES.

Field Day Learning Games.

2023

https://github.com/opengamedata/opengamedata-js-log/

Point-and-click, browser-based games targeting mobile tablets and other handheld devices.

- ♦ Built data analytics and logging tools for real-time data collection with Firebase in collaboration with the Open Game Data project
- \diamond Developed the game's dialogue system building text-parsing tooling which extended scripts written in YarnSpinner
- ♦ Adapted the game's graphics to make use of both WebGL and Canvas rendering styles to meet different tablet and mobile limitations

EDUCATION

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN CAPSTONE CERTIFICATE University of Wisconsin—Madison

2023-pres.

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Wisconsin—Madison

2019-2023

- ⋄ Certification (minor) in Game Design
- ⋄ Certification in Digital Art
- Certification in Professional Japanese Communication